# 今天早上在南昌 雪鱼将要去的是秦胖子肉坨店
This morning in Nanchang, Xue Yu is going to Qin Pang Zi’s meatball store.
# 这个名字 听起来就会觉得这顿早餐 很有分量
Hearing this name, you would feel this breakfast is quite heavy.
# 我要一个拌粉 再加一个肉坨（汤）
I want a cold rice noodle, and a meatball (soup).
# 8块5
8 Yuan 50 Cents
# 肉坨是待会放过去是吧
The meatball will be served later, right?
# 好
Ok.
# 好 谢谢
Ok, thanks!
# 这家早餐店 最特色的就是肉坨
In this breakfast store, the most special is the meatball.
# 5块钱的肉坨 这个肉坨就已经占满了整个炖盅
5 Yuan meatball. This meatball takes up the whole stew cup.
# 好大一个
So big it is.
# 除了要了5块钱的肉坨 我还要了一个3块5的拌粉
Besides of 5 Yuan meatball, I ordered another 3.5 Yuan cold rice noodle.
# （拌粉）它就是 直接把料放在上面了
(Cold rice noodle) here it is. Already add the toppings on it.
# 需要自己拌一下
I need to stir it by myself.
# 粉本来是白色的 上面加了酱油
The rice noodle was white originally, with soy source on it.
# 拌完之后就是呈现这种黄褐色
After stirring, it becomes this kind of tawny.
# 很有食欲吧
Quit appetizing, right?
# 我的辣椒还没有拌上来
My chili hasn’t been mixed well yet.
# 8块5毛钱的早餐 还是吃的很丰盛的
Breakfast costs 8.5 Yuan, and it’s quite substantial.
# 饿了一早晨了 赶快吃
Feeling hungry for the whole morning, I can’t wait to eat.
# 米粉 特别爽滑
Rice noodle is very smooth.
# 但是 我吃我还是觉得有些辣的
But for me, it’s still a bit too spicy.
# （拌粉）它的料是很简单的 有花生 酸萝卜 辣椒
The ingredients (of cold rice noodle) are simple, with peanut, sour radish, chili.
# 又放了一些香葱
Also some spring onion.
# 拌粉是凉的 吃起来特别香
Rice noodle is cold, and it’s very tasty.
# 瞬间感觉
Suddenly I feel
# 早餐有了新的口味进阶（体验）
I have a new advanced (experience) of breakfast.
# 这一个肉坨放进去
Put this meatball in.
# 瞬间感觉 幸福感爆棚
Suddenly I feel the happiness is overwhelming.
# 它这个肉是肥瘦相间的 口感特别紧实
It has lean meat mixed with fat, and the texture is very firm.
# 我感觉吃完 会 嘴上都是 一嘴的油
I feel that after eating, my lips would be full of oil.
# 嗯 这么吃起来就是肉香味十足
Hmm, eating in this way, the meat is very aromatic.
# 这就是来嗦粉的
I’m here for this rice noodle.
# 像我点的就是肉坨汤
What I ordered is meatball soup.
# 这边除了特色的肉坨汤之外 还有肉饼汤
Except for special meatball soup, it has meat pie soup here as well.
# 肉饼汤呢 就是把猪肉糜压成饼状
To make meat pie soup, press the pork mince to be a pie,
# 在上面放上鸡蛋或者桂圆这些食材 一起蒸出来
put ingredients such as an egg or longans on top of it, then steam together.
# 也是有很多人点的
A lot of people also order it.
# 这个时候正好 我们吃着肉坨汤
Right at this moment, we are having the meatball soup,
# 旁边在做着肉坨
while the owner is making meatballs.
# 这是我第一次见到 用小碟当做做肉团的工具
This is my first time to see anyone using a dish as the tool to make meatballs.
# 每一个肉团都是很实诚的
Every meatball is quite heavy.
# 那个卖肉的 经常把肉丸子拿去称
That butcher always weighs these meatballs.
# 不差一钱
Less than 5g difference.
# 就是 做了这么多年 手上已经有杆称了
Making it for so many years, I already have a scale on my hand.
# 因为我们这个东西 差不多都有数了
Because we’ve been making this one, we have the sense.
# 二两一个 一斤肉五个
2 Liang (100g) each, and 1 Jin (500g) meat for five.
# 到现在多少年了 30年了
How many years have you been making it? 30 years already.
# 这边的肉坨是不断地做 不断地蒸 不断地卖
The meatballs are being made continuously, are being steamed continuously and are being sold continuously.
# 现在又蒸了新的一锅
Now a new pot is steamed.
# 大叔 这一锅蒸了多少盅
Uncle, how many cups in this pot?
# 40分钟
40 mins.
# 大火40分钟
High heat for 40 mins.
# 里面有多少个
How many cups inside?
# 里面60个
There are 60 cups inside.
# 这家店并不大 除去了旁边煮粉 放料的位置
This store is not big. Except for space for boiling noodle and adding toppings,
# 店里面只能放下几张桌子
there’s only space for a few seats left.
# 外面的这三张小桌就是大家最常光顾的位置
These three seats outside are the most popular ones.
# 下期·辣椒饼
Next. Chili cake
# 灵魂拷问
# ——你怕辣不
Asking from the soul: do you eat spicy food?
# 关 注
# 雪 鱼  探 店
Subscribe China Food Travel